Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Print proof books, 1930-2007 and undated RL.11602
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Print proof books
1930-2007 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11602
12.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The Chicago Office opened in 1891. Collection consists of scrapbooks holding examples of print advertisements produced in a given year. Also included are slides of print advertisements made during microfilming of older proof books. Companies represented include Blockbuster, Dell, Heinz, Kimberly Clark, Kraft, Miller beer, Motorola, Nabisco, Nestle, Northwestern Mutual, Oscar Mayer and Quaker Oat. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Proof books; Proof book slides.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The Chicago Office opened in 1891.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Print proof books were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. 35mm Microfilm proofs
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Information Center records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive Advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic Advertisements
Collection Overview
Collection consists of scrapbooks holding examples of print advertisements produced in a given year. Also included are slides of print advertisements made during microfilming of older proof books. Companies represented include Blockbuster, Dell, Heinz, Kimberly Clark, Kraft, Miller beer, Motorola, Nabisco, Nestle, Northwestern Mutual, Oscar Mayer and Quaker Oat. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; H.J. Heinz Company; Kimberly-Clark Corporation; Kraft Foods Company; Miller Brewing Company; Motorola, Inc; Nabisco, Inc.; Nestlé; Oscar Mayer & Co; Quaker Oats Company
- Proof Books, 1967-2007; 1
  - Bandai, 1996-1998 (Box 1)
  - Blockbuster, 1998-2004; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Brookfield Zoo, 1998-2002 (Box 1)
  - Dell Computer, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Heinz, 1995-2001 (Box 2)
  - IT Beat, 2000 (Box 2)
  - JWT house ads, 1967-1992; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Kimberly-Clark, 2006-2007 (Box 3)
  - Kraft, 1989-1995; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Kraft, 1996-2002; 6 folders (Box 4)
  - Kraft, 2003-2007; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Louis Rich, 1994-2000 (Box 6)
  - Melitta, 2003 (Box 6)
  - Miller Genuine Draft, 1999-2000 (Box 6)
  - Motorola, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Nabisco, 1999-2002; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Nestle, 1999-2007; 6 folders (Box 7)
  - Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance, 1999-2004; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Oscar Mayer, 1989-1992; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Oscar Mayer, 1994-2001; 6 folders (Box 9)
  - Oscar Mayer, 2001-2007; 6 folders (Box 10)
  - Pagenet, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Princess Cruises, 1996-2000; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Public service advertisements, 1988-1990 (Box 11)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes American Library Association; Catholic Charities; Executive Service Corps; Metro Achievement Center; Salvation Army
  - Quaker Oats, 1985-1991 (Box 12)
    Includes Gaines, Ken-L Ration pet foods
  - Sherwin Williams, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
  - SpencerStuart.com, 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Unilever (Salon Selectives), 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Western Union, 2002-2003; 2 folders (Box 12)
- Proof Book slides, 1930-1987 and undated; 2
  - Ballard's Ovenready Biscuits, Kraft, 1932 (Box 13)
  - Cloverleaf, Kraft, 1932; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Easton's French Dressing, Gelfand's Mayonnaise, Kraft, 1930 and undated (Box 13)
  - Gelfand's Mayonnaise, Kraft, 1930 (Box 13)
  - Hyatt Hotels, 1980s (Box 13)
  - Kraft, 1930-1938; 24 folders (Box 13)
  - Kraft, 1937-1943 and undated; 17 folders (Box 14)
  - Kraft (English and French), 1932 (Box 14)
  - Kraft, Ballard Ovenready Biscuits, 1933 (Box 14)
  - Kraft, flower arrangements, 1934-1935 (Box 14)
  - Kraft, Henard's Mayonnaise, undated (Box 14)
  - Kraft, Kraco Poultry Feed, 1930-1931; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Kraft, Meyer's Drug Store, Cloverleaf Ice Cream, 1933 (Box 14)
  - McDonnell-Douglas, 1940s-1950s and undated; 3 folders (Box 14)
  - People (men and women), 1940s-1950s and undated; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Transmittal to storage records, 1984-1987; 2 folders (Box 15)